<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>JoshWood</title>
 <link href="http://joshwood.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://joshwood.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2014-07-17T14:02:31-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://joshwood.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>JoshWood</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Blogging with GitHub Pages, Jekyll and Poole</title>
   <link href="http://joshwood.github.io/2014/07/17/github-pages/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://joshwood.github.io/2014/07/17/github-pages</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As my first post I have to give props to everyone at GitHub for creating &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; which makes a hosting a blog or project site ridiculously easy. Especially if you&amp;#39;re already a GitHub user. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wont bother typing everything you can already find on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; site, but the gist of it is the following&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;message&quot;&gt;
... create a new (GitHub) repository named username.github.io, where username is your username (or organization name) on GitHub.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you do that the URL &lt;code&gt;username.github.io&lt;/code&gt; will be accessible with your repository content as the doc-root. It will take a few minutes for the initial creation, but after that it&amp;#39;s as simple as committing the content of your site to the new repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;message&quot;&gt;
One of my first questions was &quot;Can I just create anysiteiwant.github.io&quot;

Nope. It has to exactly match your username.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway... on to the really interesting stuff. It turns out &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; supports
&lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; which is 
&lt;code&gt;...a simple, blog-aware static site generator...&lt;/code&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a wonderful explanation about &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.github.com/articles/using-jekyll-with-pages&quot;&gt;Using Jekyll with GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; on the GitHub site already, so again the gist is the following &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;message&quot;&gt;
Every GitHub Page is run through Jekyll when you push content... Because a normal HTML site is also a valid Jekyll site, you don&#39;t have to do anything special to keep your standard HTML files unchanged...
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next thing you&amp;#39;ll want is a nice theme for your blog or project site. &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllthemes.org/&quot;&gt;JekyllThemes&lt;/a&gt; has quite a few but I landed on using 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://getpoole.com/&quot;&gt;Poole&amp;#39;s&lt;/a&gt;
Hyde theme. As you&amp;#39;ll see, this site is essentially 100% Hyde. I&amp;#39;m trying not to lose focus on my goal of getting my first blog up and running - so I&amp;#39;ll tinker with layouts and navigation later &amp;lt;-:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last thing I will mention is &lt;a href=&quot;http://prose.io&quot;&gt;prose.io&lt;/a&gt;. It is a web-based, Jekyll/Markdown aware editor that links to your GitHub repo. You can basically create your post in &lt;code&gt;prose.io&lt;/code&gt; and it will push it into GitHub. I have not tried it out yet but it looks interesting. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well there you go, my first post (hello world).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
